now we go to investigation of desire and
attachment and I thought to give it in
the first two words raga and rata raga
and Lux a raga rata raga Rakta so you
can learn some Sanskrit okay I think
that's good to learn three words every
day we should try that in the mixed nuts
you know seriously then it doesn't
exceed your capacity just three words
every day my mama taught me to learn
three new words every day and then in
one year you're pretty good you're
pretty good at it
okay I tried it with Chinese but I gave
up okay so here we go these are words
I'd like you to learn okay oh that's
confused it's I saw that time is
tenderly but we're going to 11:30 yeah
okay good say raga okay meaning is
desired okay raga and it became the
Hindi word for sitar song sitar song is
called raga okay he's playing a raga but
the old meaning in the gardener is
desire okay like you are addicted to
alcohol
okay you want alcohol okay that's called
raga
okay the root is Raj or Runge and it
means to to color something like in the
old days when the new nun
when you make the new nun they're
supposed to go to the garbage can and
find any cloth and then they're supposed
to sew it together to make ropes and
then they have to do lunch they have to
make it a red color or orange color
so that's called coloring okay and
cognates are orange which means to give
a color and rage which refers to the red
face of a person who okay all right got
it
so win this chapter the chapter 6 it
says we're going to investigate raga it
means desire okay let's say desire for
yo Tao turtle which I still have because
the turtle didn't make it to the fire
offering I can't believe you have all
the offerings but you don't have to no
just kidding
don't get mad next time okay then say
rakta okay and rakta means attachment
but it also means blood okay
in in in sanskrit because it's red color
okay it's the red it's called the red
thing okay now why are we talking about
these two sounds great words the name of
this chapter famous chapter six in the
gardener is raga and rata raga in Rakta
we are and what's the other word in the
name of the chapter for $10 cheap
chapter XI chapter raka raka pariksha
okay everybody get $10 next lifetime
maybe okay so rocks a raga attractor
pariksha okay we're going to investigate
raga and Rakta now that name of the
chapter is confusing because raga means
desire and reducta means attachment
usually raga means desire and rakta
means attachment okay so let's say you
first time you drink alcohol you have
raga you see you desired alcohol okay
and then you desire again and then you
desire again and then you desire again
and the raga becomes Rakta okay so you
can say desire and attachment okay or
addiction almost okay so first you have
raka raka raka raka raka did doctor
become rakta and you become attached I
don't know you buy a new car you have
raka raka raka for Tesla's day only has
a Tesla raga no guess not not Tesla
Model X right you know agar agar agar
and then you know you buy one and you
get reacted to it and then somebody
scratch it and you're like did that show
you have rakta your raga became locked
up because you get angry if someone hurt
your new Tesla okay
so usually raga means first desire and
then it grows it grows a girl's and then
you have Rakta oh I must have this thing
if someone hurt my thing I will get
angry okay now I have okay usually it
means that okay and if you try to study
this chapter like that you will fail it
doesn't mean down here okay so what does
it mean in this chapter and I made you a
note yeah it's the person
it's the raga earth is called rakta in
this chapter okay if you don't know that
and many people tried to understand this
chapter without it he doesn't tell you
and the guys in that doesn't tell you
Tony Lama tells you Tony Lamas the
amazing author of this book okay and
then this this we will translate this
book now we are translating it now it
will be about the same size okay it's
the mother book of this book but this is
the mother book of that book
so Tony Lama says don't worry listen in
this case nakta means the person who has
the raga okay the person who has to
learn okay and the other guys gonna come
and he still wants to talk about look
something's are natural some things are
natural the chemicals in your body have
a natural connection to your bones and
your skin okay
the chemicals in your body have a
natural connection to your bones and
your skin that's why I guess nah you
cannot eat chotto day after day after
day because the elements will create
different bone and more you see that
mean that's the result of the chose the
elements and then the tummy is the
result of the elements then you have
trouble in the yoga to do the uttanasana
right there's a something obstacle when
you touch your toes right okay so
there's a natural connection between
what you eat and what comes on your
tummy okay that nobody made this
connection it's a natural connection
okay what was the other connection
I should offer money but I had a big
expense this morning hmm what's the
other connection we talked about we had
three right yeah your eye and and you
know your eye must be touching the cup
somehow okay if you see the coffee there
must be some connection between your eye
on the coffee must be well you know
maybe it's particles maybe it's waves we
don't know ok scientists still don't
know something's going between ok there
is some natural connection between my
eye and that what was the last one more
difficult
no well close yeah definition and thing
yeah good that's okay you can say fire
ok nobody made fire hot ok nobody made
fire burning its natural connection if
you put a lot of logs and you light it
and you go ohms voila voila voila right
it will it will be hot and burning
ok that's fire ok nobody nobody
connected the heart to the fire it's
natural ok got it
so we're talking about natural natural
things all right now the other guy his
hole every time he comes in the
beginning of the chapter and says
something wrong he's mostly talking
about look there's a natural connection
there's a natural connection ok it's by
Nature now listen in this chapter to
important natural connections ok to
important natural connections ok and
they're both very deep ok they're both
very deep the first one
when you have an emotion in your heart
okay when you have emotion in your heart
like I'm on a churro
okay your child okay then there has to
be a connection between that feeling and
your mind natural connection okay got it
you can't want a churro if you don't
have a brain okay one thing churro is
connected to the brain okay
and by the way Tony Lama says very
important here okay ready you still with
me okay you're awful quiet
maybe you're just thinking about churros
there's a natural connection between the
person and desire
everybody has desire okay people are
like the table and desire is like the
coffee cup okay the coffee cup sit on
the table okay this is the mind of the
person this is the Rakta and this is the
raga the rector has the raga the desired
person has desired thought in their mind
okay so and Tony Lama says if you want
to go deeper which Chinese people like
to do okay Americans are like I say you
all go deeper they're like yeah okay and
if you're in China instant you want to
go deeper my god
that's why I go to China if you want to
go deeper Tony Lamas says there's two
tables there's two kinds of tables okay
that person the desirer okay
it's either the mind my mind has desire
right like my mind is like the table and
the desire is like the cup okay or you
can say the Rakta the desire is Michael
okay you can say Michael wants churro or
you can say Michaels mind wants a churro
okay so when you say rakta in this
chapter desire it can be either the
person or the mind
good okay person or the mind so the
table in this chapter that this person
who has that is who has the desire you
can say Oh Michaels mind has a desire or
you can say Michael has the desire okay
and the desire is like the cup this is
called what in sanskrit raga and this is
called rakta oh sorry tables come with
me I was just thinking about it then
this other guy he is very sophisticated
he says desire and the human mind are
connected like fire and heart desire and
the human mind are connected in a
natural way as Tina said correctly like
fire and hot okay they are connected can
you divide
hot from fire not really because that's
a definition right that's a lucky no the
natural sign of fire is hot if you took
away the heart what will happen to the
fire I don't know then if you sit next
to the fire you need to get a coat right
because it would be cold that kind of
happened last night we were all sitting
nicer fire somebody told me I got the
vows but I lost my toes yes it's very
interesting that guy is very
sophisticated that other guy right he's
not stupid he's not stupid he's saying
look the gardener if everything come
from me if the heart of the fire come
from me then the heart is not connected
to the fire naturally you know then it's
coming from my seeds okay if the husband
is angry in the kitchen come from me
then there's no connection between the
husband and the anger he's not angry I'm
angry something wrong the other guy
doesn't like it he says if the husband's
coming from me then the heart of the
fire also coming from me then the fire
doesn't need heart then there can be
fire without hunt because first there's
a fire and then I make it hot you seen I
mean then he says let's go deeper in the
Gaggia okay let's go deeper now the RB
Dharma guys they are kind of tired of
fighting they're not very strong
accountant you know and kind of getting
one of these mind only yoga teacher guys
with the big muscle and they're like hey
let's go deeper into this you know
forget the fire and the heart and all
that stuff desire is a natural part of
the human being okay you cannot have a
human being without these are
okay you take out the hot you lose the
fire you take out the desire there's no
brain especially for men right take out
the design you're gonna you cut that out
of the brain then there's no brain left
food and sex the only thing that man
think about boy then you cut all the
brain okay
you cannot remove this thing from a
human mind not possible there's a
natural connection okay got it that's
the first kind of natural connection
okay then he says and there's another
kind of natural connection between
desire and the person who has the desire
which is that you can't have desire
unless there's something to desire okay
you cannot have alcoholism without got
it
so not just talking about the desire and
the mind but talking about the desire
and what you desire there's a natural
connection they must be there at the
same time they must go together you
cannot have fire without heart you
cannot have alcoholic person without
alcohol in the world it's not possible
okay so there are two natural
connections here okay number one human
mind has desire if you take out the
desire there's no human mind they are
connected okay they must be connected
why listen
you ready here's the whole chapter we
could quit an hour early but I'm not
going to
let me think about it saying when you
say I feel like drinking wine okay I
feel like drinking wine right there's AI
and there's the feeling right I feel
like drinking wine right I feel like
drinking wine okay so there must be and
I Michael and there has to be a feeling
Michael is the table and feel like
drinking wine is the cup and I feel like
drinking wine has to go someplace can
you have a feel like drinking wine
without a person know you cannot or
brain it must be okay got it
if you have a cop you got to put it on
the table there must be a table okay you
cannot divide them okay
so we have to talk about it now so
there's two kinds of natural connection
we're going to talk about number one can
you have desire without a brain or
without a person no can I have can you
have desire without alcohol can you have
desire for alcohol without alcohol
there's two natural connections we're
talking about okay ready
now for $100
everybody's like everybody woke up
I don't know we should have another
chapter xxviii ha $100 the hon hon $100
when does it first starts the year we
have to Perisher how come everybody wake
up
when I say $100 what what's a hunt is it
the hunt or the dirt or the deal or the
dark or the lures and what part wake up
the student mind hundred dollars what's
the question I forgot the question yeah
I really did $200 if you can't give me
the question
[Laughter]
come on let's talk about connection
before even I remember yeah that's where
we were we already did that
man you guys are desperate for this
money let's go back to the text
maybe we'll get it okay maybe we'll get
it in the text Peter okay so hundred
dollars not euro folk' I told you I told
you yesterday why that cup requires a
table you have to have a person to have
desire but the question is does that
necessarily lead to that the table must
have a cup we could go there but that's
not it okay I I don't remember it was a
great question it was a hundred dollar
question let's just go okay let's just
go and we have to take a break anyway
pretty soon because it's almost break
time okay maybe I'll think of it during
the break this chapter structure oh well
let's go here okay let's go here which
exists first at the table which is poor
WA the table or the glass
which come first the table or the glass
neither one so they exist at the same
time you know I was thinking it would be
nice if the when the wife came in the
kitchen there's a bottle of wine in the
husband's hand okay okay
understand because then as I DCI one of
the qualities of DCI is it changes every
month right it grows every month we have
new ideas we we all think of new ideas
it grows you know I met somebody
recently who came to my classes 10 years
ago and we had a conversation and
they're talking I don't understand
anything they said you know they're like
generation stage I'm like what and I had
to think oh that's it I used that 10
years ago yeah yeah I remember
but I didn't they didn't take a class in
10 years you know then it's like I'm
talking to a foreigner it's like I'm
trying to talk to Chinese in Chinese you
know and so things move you know things
go on think things develop okay which
means let's put a bottle of wine in the
husband's hand in the kitchen okay then
we can have both sides of the human mind
desire and hatred right I'm angry maybe
you could leave and go get a pizza but
leave the wine okay okay you tell your
husband your husband said you're stupid
and you can say you okay since you're
not getting dinner from me why don't you
go get yourself a pizza but leave the
wine leave he has a wine in his hand
right so you tell the husband then you
can have the real Buddhist middle of the
Wheel of Life
right the snake is the anger the biggest
don't understand where your husband's
come from and what's the wine the pigeon
yeah then you have a complete wheel of
life in the kitchen I think we have to
think about it okay so let's talk about
let's forget the husband for a minute
and you are focusing on the wine like
how can I get the husband out of the
kitchen but the wines stay in the
kitchen you know and okay so you come in
and you you want the wine
okay so we got to talk about that and
after the break just before the break
we're gonna he gives a summary Tony Loma
gives a summary of the next three
chapters okay so we finished the three
accounting chapters three four and five
first one three is about the sense
powers and what they see or what they
hear we finished that one the second one
was about the parts of a person
specifically the first part of a person
and specifically the elements and the
products of the elements which is a very
Abaddon subject right we finished done
then we went to the third one which is
the elements by the way if you know
Sanskrit and if you know Tibetan it's
the come-come
petechia rub the chipper we are we are
examining come so especially in the
accounting school calm means to 18:18
parts of the world but he switch it and
the gardener switched to the other come
which is the five elements okay
including space and Heath he went to
space those are three things that the
other guys says are natural he says
those now
Tony Lamas is struggling to find a flow
in the garden his book The Guardian
looks like he's just throwing out
subjects 27 unconnected subjects okay
then Tony Lama says why why he changed a
desire why suddenly he changed the
desire okay why did he switch to desire
okay and he answers his own question as
usual and he said chapter 6 chapter 6 7
& 8 the accountants and left the room
and now somebody more sophisticated is
going to bring proofs for natural
connection proofs for natural
connections the accounts just say look
there's a connection between fire and
heart there's a natural connection
between fire and heart nobody made it
it's not coming from you
okay now three more guys come and say
look we have a proof we have proof for
natural connection we're not like those
three accounts we're better we have
proof for you we have proof why fire has
to have heart and we have proof why your
skin has to have vitamins okay and we
have proof why your eyeball has to have
you have to have an eyeball to see the
green okay green oh okay
now the next three guys we have proof
chapter 6 7 & 8
that's what we're supposed to finish by
tomorrow Oh money pay me shylu okay
first one chapter six is there a natural
connection between the mind and our
negative emotions is there a natural
connection between the mind and the
negative emotions can you cut negative
emotions out of the human mind and
there's anything left
okay where are we
we're talking about women now right cuz
I'm for men is nothing like you you cut
out desire and anger and there's no
brain left so mainly we are focusing on
women okay
[Music]
Tembo Tembo Coonan your mumble your bug
okay we're gonna fight with the guy
who say there's a natural connection
between the mind and desire okay between
the - that's chapter six okay
Chapter seven this is difficult we
already talked that all things start all
things stay and all things die okay we
talked about that already
but Chapter seven discuss does starting
have its own starting and the starting
have its own staying and the starting
have its own ending okay and there's a
special abhidharma idea I think we
talked about it if a thing starts there
should be something to start it okay if
a thing has starting there should be
something that starts the starting it's
not so crazy right I don't know it's
like a baton I'm sorry we love life
right if the Karma ripens right there
must be something that causes it to
ripen if the color starts to open there
must be some trigger that causes the
karmic destructive open okay got it
so I'll be Dharma says every beginning
has its own beginning and every
beginning has its own stain and every
beginning has its own stopping when the
staying starts
okay got it
that's all be done that's Chapter seven
okay now chapter eight and then we'll
take a break okay there's that now this
is more difficult when geshe-la drinks
the green drink okay by the way if
geshe-la drink the green drink he
doesn't have to do yoga today you
understand who's teaching yoga today oh
yeah if you drink a green drink you did
the last one so - last drinking the
green drink
okay so he won't have to do there must
be a connection
was there a green drinking yeah so there
must have been a green between car okay
that's all is there a natural connection
between karma and the person is there a
connection can you have karma without a
person and can you have a person without
Karma okay all right are those natural
all right so we're gonna take a break
but only if you can answer a question
okay $50 question we're gonna take a
break if you cannot answer it I'm gonna
keep going all right what's the two
kinds of natural connection he wants to
talk about in the sixth chapter in this
chapter can you I'll give you a clue can
you have desire without a mind and can
you have alcoholism without alcohol
$50 and you people who have to pee pee
you have to sink her okay take a break
we have to check these two connections
all right just a little bit more and the
gardener okay deep guest I remember his
question no I got excited okay I'm gonna
read you the text because it gets very
difficult and let's go slow okay
Conor rate Dutch are you a chopped-up
around shinky you don't say no okay this
is a very famous question somebody said
if someone has desire if someone wants
something then that person is really
there okay if there's desire if if some
mind wants alcohol there must be a
person there okay right if there's
alcohol wanted by some if there's
alcohol want there must be a person who
has the alcohol one okay
right you can't say look alcoholic no
person if there's a addiction to alcohol
it proves there's a person there okay
you can't have addiction to alcohol
unless it's a dog I don't know
but if you say in that room there's
addiction to alcohol there must be some
person in that room okay that's all
there's a natural connection between
addiction and the person who has a
diction you cannot have a diction
without a person right you can't say in
the men's toilet right now there's a
diction to alcohol but there's nobody
there
you can't say that okay it's natural if
there's a diction there has to be a
person okay that's all he said then we
say hmm there is no person who has an
addiction naturally there is no person
there's no connection natural connection
between the person and the addiction
okay there's no natural connection they
say there is okay if there's addiction
there must be a person if there's a
person with addiction then that
addiction they have it by nature the
connection is by nature okay there's a
nature of connection between person who
has a diction and addiction
there must be connected if the cup is
sitting on the table there must be some
connection okay it's not sitting in the
in Siberia okay next to baikal okay
make by car by color
you know impossible is here there's a
connection here this out alcoholism this
is the mind they connected okay
all right he said here's the gardener's
answer okay and we we're not going to
decide it this morning okay
but let's start okay we're just starting
Keltie do checking I don't know Dutch I
may be chopped up ocean you know okay so
what you're saying is that first there's
a person
and then later they get an addiction
right right I mean they don't come out
of their mom with addiction I mean
usually right the teenager they drink a
beer
they steal some alcohol from their
mother's house then slowly they get
addiction so can we say that first
there's a person and then later they get
a bad habit alcohol right in their mind
right no can we say that yeah okay he he
wants to say that okay killed it the
checking on the chat maybe chopped up or
she you know okay so if you say there
was a guy he was younger he didn't have
addiction and then later he got
addiction right okay you know they'll
attend a cheat day about your copay and
then you're saying that that person got
the alcoholism later right his
alcoholism came later right touch on
your burger pay from where wait don't
forget this guy doesn't accept since
this guy okay he got he didn't have
alcoholism and then later he got
alcoholism right can we say so did the
alcoholic start first or the alcoholism
start first did the non-alcoholic become
got alcoholism right and then he became
alcoholic right so first there's a no
there's a guy with no alcoholism right
then he got alcoholism then in the next
minute he became alcoholic can we say
that so you can have alkyl
no I mean come on first there's a guy
with no alcoholism right then he became
he got alcoholism alcoholism come to his
mind into his mind right and in the next
moment we can call him alcoholic right
therefore you can have alcoholism and
not be alcoholic right in the in the
first minute okay I'll say it again Yong
Yong Yong Yong Yong not alcoholic not
alcoholic not alcoholic alcoholism start
if the person get alcoholism in the next
minute we can call him you are alcoholic
right okay
so it but in the first minute that
alcoholism on his mind he's not
alcoholic right so you can be alcoholic
without alcoholism and you cannot be
alcoholic and have alcoholism right then
what will the guards in this thing show
me show me
he says something's weird something
something's wrong here let's say it
again no alcoholic no alcoholic no
alcoholic alcoholic alcoholism coming to
mind but he's not alcoholic yet because
you cannot call him alcoholic because he
didn't have alcoholism yet then after
the alcoholism come in the next hour or
the next day or the next week you say
he's alcoholic right god but in the
first moment that the alcoholism is in
the brain
there's no alcoholic right so there's
alcoholism without alcoholic right and
there's alcoholic without alcoholism
okay
the gardener want you to to think how is
that possible how is that possible
okay god it's not possible it's strange
something's wrong something's wrong I'll
say it again many years he was not
alcoholic then first moment start
alcoholism in his mind but at that
moment you cannot call him alcoholic yet
because he doesn't have it yet then he
get it
he started drink then all his family say
oh he became alcoholic right that
happens later right so you can have
alcoholism without an alcoholic I just
explained why you can have out then the
family calls your alcoholic right later
it starts to grow in your mind but
you're not alcoholic yeah and then you
get it alcohol there's some and then the
next day or the next week people say you
are alcoholic okay but if it's like the
table and the cup then you can have
alcoholic with no alcoholism or you can
have alcoholism without an alcoholic and
the cup will sit in the air right
okay they have to support each other but
they don't something's wrong okay
something's wrong but the good news is
oh by the way yeah he was alcoholic but
we didn't see the alcoholism till later
okay yes they say that in psychology oh
he got but my parents are both alcoholic
then my friends are nervous you know
they say are you nervous geshe-la why
you have alcoholic genes they say it's a
genetic they say be careful getting that
don't drink alcohol because your father
had it your mother had it so maybe you
will get it easily okay so in that case
we can say that at first I didn't have
alcoholism but I had like a seat for
alcoholism psychological seat for
alcoholism
genetics seat for alcoholism and then
later in my life I hear I smelled
alcohol
I see people drinking alcohol then I
start to drink alcohol later in my life
okay but actually I'm an alcoholic
before the alcohol because of my genes
because of my mother and father right
I'm almost alcoholic we can say almost
alcoholic okay I have genetic
predisposition for alcohol okay
so I carry it carry it but it nobody can
see it and then suddenly it shows you
know gets lost getting drunk during the
class it's not really green drink he's
drinking so can we say it's possible for
a person to have a seed of alcoholism in
their mind and it doesn't show for a
while and then it comes out so there's
the person have the seed for alcohol and
then later it comes out right we can say
desire we can call alcoholism definition
is desire for
right we can say okay so that person
looks like they don't have desire but
actually they have a seat deep inside
and then many years go by they don't
have friends who drink alcohol then they
get some friends who drink alcohol and
then they start to drink alcohol but for
many years they had they are actually
out in your alcoholic either alcoholic
okay got it correct sounds okay then the
gardener says say remember $200
remember to dot Jamba Jamba rim button
give me it right or don't give me at all
and I didn't forget the question
remember - did I say $100 I didn't say
50 remember to draw Chamba I wanted
something like something come on god
soon I gave you yesterday but that was a
long time ago if you give me the answer
they can go home they can have lunch or
yoga well I'm saying I'm just explaining
something connection equal remember to
Jamba yeah forget it it's too expensive
yeah I remember mean steps okay then the
gardener says then then our heart is the
same what our heart raced Nirvana they
removed that table or they remove the
cup yeah then we moved the car they
removed desire from the mind right but
he's gonna become alcoholic later right
so no our hats right not possible
there's natural connection alcoholism
and desire and the mind right if it
looks like he don't have desire you
cannot trust it because the desire will
maybe come up later
yeah or it doesn't need a natural
connection garden okay you have to cook
it the point is if a person without
alcoholism can get alcoholism then a
person without desire can get desire
then there's no Nirvana then there's no
Nirvana then Nirvana not possible if
there's a natural connection between
people and desire then there's no
Nirvana because that's like the boy you
cut out the desire and there's no
brainer cuz that's a male right not a
female okay
right only boys have this problem okay
let's stop there and just think about it
okay the question is is fire and hot the
same as desire and human mind or can you
cut out the desire and the mind is still
there okay or not well then no nirvana
and we shouldn't be here we should be
drinking
all right I would like to we have about
a half hour before friends have to some
friends have to leave we require for you
what you told me 10 ACOG you cheat me
again
ok 9:45 yeah ok 13 minutes to finish the
gardener I can do it I with no stress I
can do
we finished three and a half chapter
okay I don't forget I owe you two and a
half more chapters right don't worry I
didn't forget but we did them correctly
and we did them slow so you got that Tim
I'm going to show you the first minute
ok Tim I have a video ok can you turn on
the projector cool ok the first chapter
that we studied was an erection of the
indriyas of the eye and the object ok so
there's a cute video that I I often
enjoy ok there's a what's it called
Heisman uncertainty principle Heisenberg
uncertainty principle
it means a there's a problem in quantum
physics with how we see things there's a
problem how light comes from the Sun to
the earth ok there's a problem and
Stephen Hawking couldn't figure it out
but we figured it out ok so here's the
problem you ready and I'm not going to
show the whole thing Oh money pay me
home
quantum mean weird negation are weird
[Music]
are they
okay this is Nagaya it doesn't make
sense okay and still in quantum physics
we still don't know how does the
sunlight reach the earth you know we
will die without the Sun we will have no
food we will have no suntan and how does
it come from the Sun we don't know okay
how does it come from the Sun this is
Chapter three okay he's teaching chapter
three how does it come from the Sun good
say it louder
for $0 a seat that comes from my mind
opens and it creates me and the sunlight
reaching the earth okay got it got it
how did the Sun light come to this earth
its seed opening in your mind okay
how does food grow from the Sun crops
it's coming from you okay so that covers
chapter three we finished chapter three
chapter four where wasn't examination of
the state of Sanskrit no examination of
prediction of
yeah skander right examine the five
parts of the person right so for this we
can what's weird about the elements
right and the results of the elements
what's weird about them is aspirin okay
aspirin it has a chemical inside and
then when we get a headache
our mom tada your I might I remember my
mom told me take a husband if you get I
used to get read bad headaches when I'm
a kid and my mom will say oh just take a
spin and then I remember one day nothing
happened
I remember which bed I mean my brother's
bed I couldn't even go to my room I
couldn't reach my room and I'm in my
brother's bed she gave me a spin nothing
happened
then I asked mom I called my mom it
didn't work I still have a headache she
said Oh take a second one didn't I take
a second one you know ten minutes later
it's still the same Hannah you know then
I called my mom a mom I need another
Aspen then she I remember she pick up
the bottle and she said it's a only two
for kids only two she said I'm sorry you
cannot have another one I said but mom I
still have a headache she said then she
said very bad bad bad things she said
sometimes you just have to have him and
I'm like oh then we always believe our
mom we always be okay mom she says
sometimes the Aspen work and sometimes
the Aspen don't work okay honey it's
like that life is like that she lied to
me okay she was a bad plumber she didn't
tell me the truth okay she didn't
understand the guardzilla Chapter four
she believed that when he come to kinds
of atoms in the molecule in the aspirin
she believed in okay there's two kinds
of atoms in the molecule she believed it
Aspen has especial atoms
Aspen has a special molecules okay she
believed it okay understand so that's a
second example that's Chapter four we
want a real example gusta la we want
real example okay what was Chapter three
sunlight how it reached the earth what
was Chapter four aspirin was Chapter
five yes base and the definition of
space and luck China on the fire states
the hot and burning
nobody glue it nobody took the heart and
burning and put it on the fire it's a
latina it's a sign of that thing it's
the sign of that thing that's Chapter
five
okay then fire is not coming the heart
of fire if not coming what's a practical
use what's a practical use then I
remember I gave this teaching in New
York just before my three-year between
then it was very difficult
I taught eighteen HCI courses then it
was very difficult
I made an announcement I'm leaving New
York then everyone's like oh yeah I
remember I stood up I said I'm leaving
New York I have to go you know and I'm
doing three or between in Arizona in the
desert and everyone and I said I will
give one more teaching at the World
Trade Center we went to the World Trade
Center you either and I gave the
teaching at the bottom of the World
Trade Center and I said the steel in
this building has lection er right it's
hard
and it can hold up the big building
right what's holding up the World Trade
Center is the steel and inside it has
lucky no hard strong hard and strong
right know that hardens I remember I
gave this talk last thing I did in New
York it's not steep it's not the lacuna
it's not the hard and it sea and it's
not hard and it's not the strong is in
this deal ok it's not the hard and this
chunk is in the steel ok
what's keeping up this roof is it the
walls yeah your karma your sins okay
your seats to keep up this roof it's not
the bricks okay forget it they're not
doing it don't think like that if you
want to have a roof over your head we
say in English if you want to have a
apartment if you want to have a place to
stay you must do the 13-step Tolan on
other people you must give them places
to stay and if you don't that building
will fall down what happened yeah I went
into 303 you know and I remember there
were many military planes suddenly we
are in the middle of the desert
then suddenly many planes practicing
Jews using really long you know we are
like out here you know and yeah what's
going on you know we don't know then
when we came out of retreat that
newspaper came the big newspaper Benson
it has three pages and they came to
interview us they said you are the only
people in the world who don't know and
we said what they said World Trade
Center fell down I'm like oh yeah okay
okay understand now last one then you
guys can go I still have 30 seconds okay
Stanley when the wife come in the
kitchen and the man start to yeah
husband start to yell I imagine okay
there's a yo Chow at the table what
happens when you feel stress at home
sometimes you eat too much that's why we
did fine you know with too much stress
even Geshe Michael when he go home at
night last night I ate three bowls of
cereal before go to bed because I'm
tired then the wife also think Oh
husband is not nice to me I have to eat
something
to feel happy you know the yo cha will
make me happy okay listen the gardener
doesn't like it
the your town will make me happy he's
like which part of the hotel touch my
tongue oh that's it touch it tongue yeah
time to tell me your tongue no it
doesn't the in front of your child has a
tongue tongue where does the front of
the hotel touch the front of the not
possible
and it's very that's the rest of chapter
six okay the sugar crystal never touched
the tongue okay if they touch they have
to go into each other like this you see
they cannot touch like this okay if they
touch then a little bit of the sugar has
to become a little bit of the tongue you
see I understand then the sugar have to
become the tongue it's not possible okay
oh well what if the sugar doesn't become
the tongue well then they cannot affect
each other
okay cannot understand if they're sure
can give taste to the tongue without
mixing then the poopoo also will give
taste to the tongue because they also
don't mix understand that this special
poopoo treasure-house the white one
everything inside will give you good
taste
why guess not why you say that because
the sugar give you good taste
well no the sugars in my mouth no the
sugar is not in your mouth it cannot
touch no it touch if it touch it cover
each other if it touch them mix if you
touch them mix understand then for sugar
to give you good taste to the wife in
the kitchen because she's nervous right
the husband yell at her right if the
sugar give the taste there has to be a
little mix there has to be a little mix
if there's no mix then the poopoo in the
bathroom also gives a good taste at the
same time because they also don't mix
the poopoo also don't mix with the
tongue and that sugar they also don't
mix with the tongue so everything that
don't mixed with the tongue should give
the taste garden or if they do mix then
the tongue is sugar it's not possible
it's the same as the professor in the
cartoon he's like it's not possible that
the wife can feel better by eating the
note it's not possible not possible it's
impossible okay last question then you
have to go Timmy has to make him Nelson
maybe why that's the wife feel more when
you call comfort after the husband angry
and go away if she eat the yo tell why
Geshe Michael eats three bowls of sweet
cereal last night why why she wants to
eat she she wants to feel relaxed she
wants comfort husband is angry I need
some your tongue I need some I need
something sweet
it's
too much stress so she eat right does
the hotel give the sweet taste no does
the yota give the comfort what gives the
comfort 13-step Tolman 13-step told man
okay then that karma come to you through
the OTO garden later you don't need the
yoga you can be skinny and you can feel
good about your husband okay that's how
we use those four chapters okay that's
how use the four chapters okay it's not
TV use them where use them in the Tomlin
use them in the thirteenth steps okay in
the gardener and the tongue men got
married this morning understand okay Tim